<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Umer Jamil </title>
    <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Umer Jamil </description>
    <image>
      <url>https://umerjamil16.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://umerjamil16.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hitting Sixes to No Balls in Your Career: Identifying Pivotal Moments for Asymmetric Returns</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/asymmetric-opps-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/asymmetric-opps-career/</guid>
      <description>While many career opportunities yield symmetrical rewards, there are brief moments that can have outsized impact on your career trajectory. These pivotal moments, whether it be a meeting with a high-level executive or a small action with a large impact, require careful attention and recognition to make the most of the opportunity. Volunteering for activities with visibility or impact is one of the strongest ways to directly impact your career. Don&amp;rsquo;t miss out on hitting those sixes to no balls in your career - identify and seize pivotal moments for asymmetric returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistency as a Strategic Advantage</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/consistency-strategic-adv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/consistency-strategic-adv/</guid>
      <description>(A view of Hunza Valley, Pakistan)
Consistency is a crucial factor that can significantly impact one&amp;rsquo;s personal and professional life. It is often overlooked and not given the attention it deserves. People tend to view consistency as a property or characteristic of some kind, rather than a strategic advantage in a competitive sense.
As I have had conversations with individuals in leadership roles, such as CEOs, CTOs, professors, and entrepreneurs, I have realized that they see consistency as a key to their success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beginner&#39;s Guide to GPUs for Machine Learning Workloads</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/guide-gpu-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/guide-gpu-ml/</guid>
      <description>This blog aims to provide a basic understanding of GPUs for ML/MLOps Engineers, without going into extensive technical details. The focus will be on developing a broad knowledge of GPUs to aid in hardware decision-making for managing ML/DL workloads and pipelines. This blog will not include comparisons of different GPU architectures for ML workloads.
Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s review some key terminologies that will be used throughout this blog:
 Latency: The time delay between the initiation of a task and the detection of its effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerizing Kaldi - the speech recognition toolkit</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/kaldi_docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/kaldi_docker/</guid>
      <description>Kaldi is a very popular Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) toolkit. In my experience, setting up Kaldi on a system can take huge amount of time. Therefore, it is best to use containerization approach.
Following is the Dockerfile that I wrote. We will be using a cuda enabled Ubuntu 18.04 image from Nvidia NGC:
FROM nvidia/cuda:11.1.1-cudnn8-devel-ubuntu18.04 LABEL Author=&amp;#34;umerjamil16@github.io&amp;#34; Email=&amp;#34;umer1694@gmail.com&amp;#34; LABEL Description=&amp;#34;Kaldi ASR Image&amp;#34; Vendor=&amp;#34;x&amp;#34; Version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34; RUN sh -c &amp;#39;echo &amp;#34;APT { Get { AllowUnauthenticated \&amp;#34;1\&amp;#34;; }; };&amp;#34; &amp;gt; /etc/apt/apt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to DevOps</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/devops-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/devops-intro/</guid>
      <description>DevOps is the evolution of software development lifecycle. Last week, at Rayn, I gave a talk on DevOps, the process, the methodology, and how adopting DevOps methodology can help IT and business teams. The presentation content is as follows:
Thank you for for your time. Hope you liked the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS S3 - Notes</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/aws-s3-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/aws-s3-notes/</guid>
      <description>AWS S3 S3 is the most famous and earliest product by AWS. Following here are my notes about it.
Storage Types There are three main storage types:
 Block Storage File Storage Object Storage  Block Storage   Block storage is an architectural design that enables the storage of data onto media such as a hard disk, in fixed-sized chunks.
  On AWS, block storage options are available as Elastic Block Store (EBS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attributes of High Performance Engineering Teams by Zia Syed | Emumba Tech Talks | Notes</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/attr-high-perf-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 19:42:38 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/attr-high-perf-teams/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had the chance to listen to a talk by Zia Syed (14+ years at Google, 20 years in industry). The talk was focused on what are the attributes of high performance engineering teams. It is available on YouTube [here]
Following are my notes and some of the points presented by Zia.
 Clarity of Purpose  This is a must thing. Having personal and work level OKRs to bring clarity, clear mandate and ownership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing tp-link Archer T2U plus WiFi adapter drivers on Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/post-tp-link-a2u-plus-wifi-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 19:42:38 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/post-tp-link-a2u-plus-wifi-adapter/</guid>
      <description>So recently I bought a tp link Archer T2U plus wifi adapter and install it drivers on my Ubuntu 20.04 laptop. Here are the installation steps I went through:
1. Check USB connection
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; lsusb Bus 004 Device 001: ID 1d6b:0003 Linux Foundation 3.0 root hub Bus 003 Device 004: ID 04f2:b735 Chicony Electronics Co., Ltd HP Wide Vision HD Camera Bus 003 Device 003: ID 046d:c542 Logitech, Inc. Wireless Receiver Bus 003 Device 005: ID 8087:0026 Intel Corp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is Suffering: Confronting Existential Reality and Taking Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/life-suffering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/life-suffering/</guid>
      <description>It is a daunting reality to acknowledge that life is suffering. In contemporary culture, there is a focus on hedonism, nihilism, victimhood, and the pursuit of short-term pleasures. However, when we consider the fundamental reality of life, it becomes clear that suffering is at its core. When something bad or unexpected happens, pain is present. While some may argue that suffering is not the fundamental reality, it cannot be denied that it exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auschwitz, Nihilism and Man’s Search for Meaning</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/man-search-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/man-search-meaning/</guid>
      <description>The article is a compilation of my observations and reflections while reading &amp;ldquo;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&amp;rdquo; by Dr. Victor Frankl and listening to Dr. Jordan Peterson&amp;rsquo;s lectures on uncovering the psychological significance of Biblical stories. Dr. Frankl, a Holocaust survivor who endured the concentration camps of Theresienstadt, Auschwitz, Kaufering, and Türkheim, has authored 29 books based on his experiences. Dr. Peterson is a distinguished clinical psychologist and professor at the University of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
