<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Umer Jamil </title>
    <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Umer Jamil </description>
    <image>
      <url>https://umerjamil16.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://umerjamil16.github.io/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life is Suffering: Confronting Existential Reality and Taking Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/life-suffering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/life-suffering/</guid>
      <description>It is a daunting reality to acknowledge that life is suffering. In contemporary culture, there is a focus on hedonism, nihilism, victimhood, and the pursuit of short-term pleasures. However, when we consider the fundamental reality of life, it becomes clear that suffering is at its core. When something bad or unexpected happens, pain is present. While some may argue that suffering is not the fundamental reality, it cannot be denied that it exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auschwitz, Nihilism and Man’s Search for Meaning</title>
      <link>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/man-search-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://umerjamil16.github.io/posts/man-search-meaning/</guid>
      <description>The article is a compilation of my observations and reflections while reading &amp;ldquo;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&amp;rdquo; by Dr. Victor Frankl and listening to Dr. Jordan Peterson&amp;rsquo;s lectures on uncovering the psychological significance of Biblical stories. Dr. Frankl, a Holocaust survivor who endured the concentration camps of Theresienstadt, Auschwitz, Kaufering, and Türkheim, has authored 29 books based on his experiences. Dr. Peterson is a distinguished clinical psychologist and professor at the University of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
